oasisoftheseas.com 2014-07-03

# Privacy Policy - Allure of the Seas | Oasis Of The Seas

**  
The Information We Gather**  
We collect information about you through two principal means: through technology (for example, IP addresses and cookies) and through your voluntary submission of information. _1\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information_  
Using technology, our sites can collect information about the type of browser you are using, your operating system and your IP address information. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer and is recognized by Web technology whenever you are surfing the Internet. None of this information is considered personally identifiable information. As technology evolves, additional methods of information gathering may be used, such as "pixel tags" (also known as "web beacons" and "clear gifs"). 

We also use cookies and other technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information for a variety of purposes, such as to improve the design and content of our website and to enable us to provide a more personalized experience when you browse the Internet. Most industry-standard Web browsers have an option that allows you to turn off all cookies or have your computer inform you each time that a request to place a cookie is being made. If you turn cookies off (or refuse to accept a request to place a cookie), you may not have access to some features on our websites and some of our services, such as purchasing a cruise or being automatically recognized as a loyalty member. 

We may provide aggregate non-personally identifiable information to third parties (such as marketers, ad-server companies and advertisers) that make use of general customer data. We may also share that information with concessionaires aboard our ships and other third parties. 

RCCL is not liable for information that is inaccurate due to technical defects in software used on our websites, whether induced by our systems or by software provided by third parties. 

_2\. Personally Identifiable Information_  
You can use the majority of our websites without being required to divulge any personally identifiable information to us. To participate in or use some of the activities available on our sites (such as purchasing a cruise or entering a contest or contacting us) you may be required to provide certain personally identifiable information (such as your name and e-mail address). In addition, in connection with some activities, such as purchasing a cruise, we collect additional personally identifiable information such as your date of birth, street and billing address and credit card number. 

When corresponding with you via e-mail, we may use a variety of technologies, such as "clear gifs" or "web beacons," to let us know, among other things, whether you received and opened our e-mail. The clear gif included in the e-mail may establish a cookie on your system that further allows us to tailor information to fit your personal interests.

RCCL will not trade, sell or share such personally identifiable information for use by any third parties unless we have informed you, been authorized by you or are required by law to do so. In addition, such personally identifiable information shall not be disclosed to third parties unless we have informed you, been authorized by you or are required by law to do so. The term "third parties" does not include any subsidiaries or affiliates of RCCL, service providers or vendors acting on RCCL's behalf or travel agents or the purchaser of substantially all of the assets of RCCL or a subsidiary or affiliate of RCCL. Our policy is to require that third parties keep that information confidential. We reserve the right to disclose personally identifiable information, without notice, if we believe that such action is necessary to defend and protect the rights or property of RCCL and its family of websites or to protect the personal safety of users of RCCL, its websites or the public.

Your credit card number is used to process your request for products or services and will not be shared with third parties that are not involved with the transaction.

**How We Use the Information Gathered**  
We use the information that you share with us for these purposes: **How Do I Change My Personally Identifiable Information Or Tell Royal Caribbean That I Don't Want to Be Contacted?**  
Our websites sometimes provide you the opportunity to choose to receive communications from us when we request information from you. You always have the option of removing your name from our e-mail mailing list(s) so that you will not receive further e-mail promotional communications from us. In order to ensure immediate removal from any list, it is best to follow the specific instructions outlined within the communications you receive from us, since we operated numerous sites and e-mail lists. If you are unable to complete the process indicated in such communications, [send us an e-mail](http://www.royalcaribbean.com/customersupport/contactUsOnline.do). **Links and Third Parties**  
Our websites often provide links to resources that we believe may be useful. These links will lead you to websites operated by third parties that operate under different privacy policies. We encourage you to review those privacy policies, as we have no control over information you may submit to those third parties. 

Our websites may use third parties, such as ad-server companies, to present or serve advertisements that you may see on our website. Our websites may also include advertisements placed by third parties. Our privacy policy does not cover any information collected by those third parties nor does it cover how they may use such information.

**How Do We Protect Your Information?**  
Security for all personally identifiable information is extremely important to us. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the correct usage of information, we monitor and adjust our physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

Unfortunately, we cannot guarantee that data transmitted over the Internet will always be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products and services and you do so at your own risk. Upon receipt of your transmission, we strive to ensure the security of that information in our systems.

**What About Children Under the Age of 13?**  
None of our websites are targeted at children (minors under thirteen years of age) and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children who have not obtained parental consent. **Privacy Policy Updates**  
By using our websites, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. RCCL reserves the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this policy at any time. Visitors are encouraged to review this policy from time to time to stay abreast of any changes. Your continued use of our websites following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept those changes. **Questions or Comments?**  
If you have any further questions or comments **regarding our Privacy Policy** , please [send us an e-mail](http://www.royalcaribbean.com/customersupport/contactUsOnline.do) with your questions or comments. 

This privacy policy was last modified on March 20, 2002.
